EMMANUEL MMEAH

P. O. Box 36 Sefwi Bekwai, Ghana

+233249126494, +233203584285 | LinkedIn : https://github.com/Nuel1987 | Email: emmameah@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE:

A proactive and adaptable professional with extensive expertise in ICT, network administration, and project management. With strong analytical skills and experience in telemedicine and business platforms, I am dedicated to contributing to the success of forward-thinking organizations.

EDUCATION:

August, 2024 – December, 2024

Power Learn Project Africa

Software engineering

September, 2020 – June, 2022

University of International Business and Economic - China

Master of Science Industrial Economics (International Business and Cross Border E-Commerce)

August, 2008 - May, 2012

University of Ghana

Bachelor of Arts (Information Studies and Political Science)

September, 2004 – June, 2007

Sefwi Bekwai Secondary School

WASSCE

WORK EXPERIENCE:

2024 Lead Developer | Telemedicine Platform

- Developed a comprehensive telemedicine platform with features like appointment scheduling, patient management, and secure consultations.
- Integrated MySQL for database management and utilized Node.js for backend development.

2024 Project Lead | Youth Entrepreneurship Hub

- Led the creation of an online platform to connect young entrepreneurs with mentors and funding opportunities.
- Responsible for backend development using Node.js and MySQL database architecture.

2021 Regional Trainer | Ghana Statistical Service

- Conducting effective training of field personnel
- Planning and supervising of field practice
- Managing logistics
- Daily reporting and feedback

•

2013 - Present ICT Tutor and Network Administrator | Awaso Academy International

- ICT tutor (Grade 6 to Grade 9)
- Assess and profile ICT equipment and advice on their relevance
- Make an assessment of existing e-tools being used in the school
- System Maintenance
- Management of e-learning plat form for 9th graders
- Software installation
- Configure network hardware such as servers, routers and switches
- Troubleshoot various network issues
- Upgrade, repair and maintain computer networks

2017 – 2020. Administrative Assistant. | C Darkwa Co. Ltd

- Managing and distributing of information within an office
- Sending and receiving corresponding
- Handling office tasks as filling, generating reports and presentation

2011 Maintenance Planner | Africa Mining Service (AMS) – Chirano

- Updating the Database of oil taken from Shell
- Taking the Engine hours of the various machines on site
- Checking when a car is due for servicing and repairs

RESEARCH PROFILE:

Electronic Commerce Adoption by Ghanaian SMEs insight from Technology Organization Environment framework perspective.

OUALITIES AND SKILLS:

SKILLS

- Technical: MySQL, Node.js, Software Development, Database Management, Networking
- Soft Skills: Communication, Teamwork, Client-Oriented
- Tools: SPSS, e-Learning Management, Project Management

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills
- Flexible and adaptable
- Dedicated, ambitious, and hardworking

CERTIFICATION:

Data Security & Cyber Laws | Indian Institute of Social Reform & Research | Dec 2021

Regional Trainer (Censuses & Surveys) | Statistical Service Ghana | May 2021

Intermediate Accounting | Udemy | Mar 2020

SPSS Certification | University of Ghana | Apr 2011

Computer Programming | Ipro Solution | Mar 2011 – Jun 2012

Computer Training (eCDLP) | University of Ghana | Mar 2009 – Nov 2009

Financial Accounting | GIMPA | Mar 2009